Guide to the Ruth M. Harris Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Ruth M. Harris Papers
1945-2013
RG 171
Yale University Divinity School Library
9
(18 boxes)
These papers document the work of various student Christian movements from the 1950s through the 1990s and the activities of the World Student Christian Federation Trustees, particularly in preparation for the WSCF Centennial and the Women's History Project. Ruth M. Harris was a leader in United Methodist and ecumenical student Christian work.
Harris, Ruth M.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ruth M. Harris.
Biographical / Historical
19xx B.A.. Morningside College, Sioux City, IA
19xx M.A., Teacher's College, Columbia University
1947-1951 Missionary teacher in China
1954-1959 Field program director for Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions
1960-1965 United Methodist Board of Global Ministries, Women's Division, student work
1965-1969 UMBGM, World Division, University world
1977-1990 UMBGM, World Division, Global justice
Scope and Contents
The papers have been retained in the order in which they were received from Ms. Harris. The material in Series I documents the work of various student Christian organizations in the U.S. from the 1950s through the 1990s. Series II documents Harris' s work with the World Student Christian Federation Trustees and Senior Friends. This series includes minutes of the Trustees from 1989 to 1999 and documentation of the Trustees' Centennial Program. Series III provides a chronological sequence of materials documenting interregional and regional activities of the the WSCF. Of particular interest is documentation of the WSCF Women's Commission and Women's History Project.
A number of printed publications received with the Harris Papers have been integrated with the Divinity Library's cataloged collections of books and periodicals, or into archival record groups related to the World Student Christian Federation (Record Group No. 46) or World Council of Churches (Record Group No. 162.) Cataloged publications include the following:
World Student Christian Federation publications:
Student World, 1951-1969
Federation News (WSCF Ecumenical Assistance Program), 1955-1968
WSCF Journal, 1979-1995
Presence (WSCF magazine for African Christian students), 1969-1970
WSCF Asia Book Series, 1977-1995
Praxis (Newsletter of Asia / Pacific WSCF)
WSCF History Series
Other books, pamphlets, and reports
World Council of Churches publications:
News Sheet (Youth Department), 1958-1959
Risk (Youth Department), 1966-1974
Study Encounter (Division of Studies), 1965-1975
Other books, pamphlets, and reports
Methodist publication:
Motive Magazine
The Ruth M. Harris Papers complement a number of other personal papers and archival collections at the Yale Divinity School Library, including the Margaret Flory Papers and the Archives of the WSCF, Student Christian Movement of New England, and University Christian Movement.
Arrangement
I. Student Christian Movements in the United States
II. World Student Christian Federation Trustees
III. World Student Christian Federation Activities
IV Addendum
Church work with students; Harris, Ruth M.; World Student Christian Federation; World's Student Christian Federation
- Student Christian Movements in the United States, Series I
  - Context, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - United Student Christian Movement, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - United Student Christian Council (USCC) Newsletter, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - USCC: General Assembly, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - USCC: XV General Assembly, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - USCC: Publications, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Methodist Student Movement (MSM): National Student conference, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - MSM: National Student conference, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - MSM: National Student Conference, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
  - MSM: National Student Conference, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Student Volunteer Movement (SVM): Tracey Jones, National Chair Address, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - SVM :National Ecumenical Conference on Christian World Mission- Athens, Ohio, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - SVM :Publications, 1954-1960 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - SVM: Ecumenical Conference on Christian World Mission- Athens, Ohio, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Other Movements, Organizations: YMCA-YWCA Conference, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Other Movements, Organizations: Christian Faith and Life Community, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - Other Movements, Organizations: Northern Student Movement, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - National Student Christian Federation (NSCF), 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Commission on World Mission of the NSCF (CWM, formerly SVM): Paper -"Christian Mission" by Lesslie Newbiggin, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Commission on World Mission of the NSCF (CWM): Paper - "The Mood on Campus" by C. Alton Robertson, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - CWM: Athens Conference, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - CWM: Newsletter, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - University Christian Movement (UCM) Newsletter - Wind and Chaff, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - UCM: Context: New Left, Drugs, Hippies, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - UCM: National Ecumenical Student Christian Conference - "Process '67" - Cleveland, Ohio, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - UCM: "Process '67" Report and Interpretation of a Survey of Conference Participants, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Study: "Religion and Political Orientation" by David Wylie, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Paper: "No Fish in the Sea" (SCM) by Roy, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - New SCMs in the USA (1975-81): Seminar at Blue Ridge Assembly (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - New SCMs in the USA: California, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - New SCMs in the USA: New York, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - New SCMs in the USA: New England, 1975-1981 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Overview Paper: "Christian Student on the Move" by Jordan, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Overview Paper: "Goodly Heritage of a Century of SCM" by Woo, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - National Ecumenical Student Christian Conference (NESCC): Steve Unruhe articles (The Beginnings) (Box 17, Folder 261)
  - NESCC: Steering Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 262)
  - NESCC: National Planning Committee, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 263)
  - NESCC: Local Planning Committee and Conference, University of Carlifornia Berkeley, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 264)
  - National Interim Committee (NIC), NESCC Follow-up: NIC Post Conference, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 265)
  - NIC, NESCC Follow-up: Important NESCC Documents, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 266)
  - WSCF/Church Relations Committee (WSCF/CRC) - Fund Raising and Interpreting Agencies, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 267)
  - WSCF/CRC, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 268-272)
  - NESCC, 1982-1986 (Box 17, Folder 273)
  - NESCC (SCM in USA), 1983-1984 (Box 18, Folder 274)
  - United Methodist National Student Conference in St. Louis - "Jubilee", 1987 (Box 18, Folder 275)
  - Jubilee "87" Methodist Student Movement, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 276)
  - Student Christians in the 1990s: Council for Ecumenical Student Christian Ministries (CESCM); "By Faith Celebrate!" by Gayla Spicknall (Box 18, Folder 277)
  - CESCM, 1993-1994, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 278-279)
  - CESCM: " Celebrate" Natioinal Student Conference, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 280)
- World Student Christian Federation Trustees, Series II
  - Senior Friends
    - Directories: Senior Friends, 1980-1995, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 38-42)
    - Directory: Membership list, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Minutes, Committee Records
    - Trustees Minutes, 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 44-49)
    - Nominating Committee, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Centennial Steering Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Trustees Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 52-53)
    - Centennial expanded Steering Committee, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Trustees Minutes, 1995 Nov (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Trustees Minutes, 1996-1999 (Box 5, Folder 56-60)
  - Trustees Centennial Program: Special Events
    - Important Documents, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Minutes, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Meeting of work group, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Planning (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Mailing From Alford, 1994 Aug (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Minutes, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Washington DC Planning, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 67-69)
    - Harris - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Packets (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Urbana, IL (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Cambridge, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Task Group, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Program Financing Summary, 1991-1994 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - New York City (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Centennial Fund
    - US Committee, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - Proposal for U.S. Participation (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - US Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 79-81)
    - Solicitation to Foundations, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Centennial History
    - US Trustees History Work Group, 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - Women's History project proposal, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - Summary: Work of WSCF with university, 1945-1990 (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - Paper "Experiment in Ecumenism 1944-59", by H. Jensen (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - Centennial History and Archives: UCM Articles (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - SCM's History - Article by Jensen and Woo (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - Bibliographies Re US SCM, Jensen and Woo (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Articles on Women: E. Anderson and Alison (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - Douglas Sloan "The Crisis in the University", 1949-1969 (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - The Demise of UCM, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - "History of the University Christian Movement" by P. Kim, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - Trustees History Work Group, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 94-99)
    - Consultation with Philip Potter re. Publishing (1), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 100-101)
    - Journal on Ecumenical Studies, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - Journal on Ecumenical Studies (JES) V.32 N.3-4 on "Perspectives on Ecumenical Christian Presence in US", edited by L. Newton Thurber, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 103-104)
    - Original articles and drafts: Chapter I: The 1960s (Box 7, Folder 105)
    - Original articles and drafts: Chapter II: The 1970s (Box 7, Folder 106)
    - Original articles and drafts: Chapters III, IV: The 1980s, The 1990s (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - Original articles and drafts: Chapter V: YMCA-YWCA and the Denominations (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - Original articles and drafts: Chapter VII: Issues/ Areas of Concern (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - Original articles and drafts: Chapter VIII: Women in the US Society (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - Original articles and drafts: Chapter IX: Special Ministries and Program Emphasis (Box 8, Folder 111)
    - Original Articles and drafts: Chronology- Appendix B and Bibliography - Appendix C (Box 8, Folder 112)
    - Articles in Journals by Ruth M. Harris (Box 8, Folder 113)
    - Correspondence w/ Harris :Re: Ecumenical Articles (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - NESCC Correspondence w/ Harris and Authors of Articles (Box 8, Folder 115)
- World Student Christian Federation Activities, Series III
  - Early History
    - "A Year of Progress in the WSCF" March 1900 - February 1901 (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - "WSCF: The Student Christian Movement of 1905" (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - "Christ and the Student World, 1920-21" (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - WSCF Interregional Directories (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - WSCF By Laws (Box 9, Folder 120)
    - WSCF Worship: Universal Day of Prayer for Students, 1955, 1963, 1981, 1987,1996 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - The Sixties
    - Interregional
      - Life and Mission of the Church Conference, Strasbourg, France, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 122)
      - WSCF General Committee, Thessaloniki, Greece, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 123)
      - WSCF EXCO, Geneva, Switzerland, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 124)
      - Consulation on Students Studying Abroad, Celigny, Switzerland, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 125)
      - WSCF General Assembly - Argentina, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 126)
      - WSCF Revised Requests, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 127)
      - WSCF Executive Committee Summary, Helsinki Finland, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 128)
      - Seminar on the Role of Students in Development, Denmark, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 129)
      - Four Year Report: "Life and Work of WSCF", 1964-1968 (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - Regional: Africa
      - 3rd Annual Africa Student Seminar in Europe,1961; 6th Seminar, 1964; 7th Seminar, 1965, 1961-1965 (Box 9, Folder 131)
      - Consultation on the Christian Community in the Unversities of Africa (WSCF and All Africa Conference of Churches), 1966 (Box 9, Folder 132)
    - Regional: Asia
      - 5th Asian Student Christian Conference in Europe, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 133)
      - Consultation on Ecumenical Strategy in the Universities in Asia, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 134)
      - 7th and 8th Asian Student Christian Seminars, 1966, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 135)
      - China Study Vol. I, China Working Group, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 136)
      - China Study Vol. II, China Working Group, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 137)
      - Footnotes, Vol. I No. 1, 1968 Dec (Box 10, Folder 138)
      - Lectures: "China and the Great Cultural Revolution", Canada, Japan, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 139)
      - Asia Study Fellowship, Geneva, Switzerland, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 140)
    - Regional: Europe
      - Consultation on Christian Presence in Higher Education, Basel, Switzerland (WSCF and Conference of European Churches), 1967 (Box 10, Folder 141)
      - Minutes on European Staff Meeting, Geneva, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 142)
    - Regional: Middle East
      - 4th Middle Eastern Student Seminar in Europe, Geneva, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 143)
  - The Seventies
    - Interregional
      - WSCF Newsletter, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 144)
      - WSCF Executive Committee, Tozanso, Japan, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 145)
      - WSCF Visit to Korea, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 146)
      - WSCF Report, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 147)
      - The Struggle for East Timor; Bible Study Meditations by Campi, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 148)
      - WSCF Annual Report; "The Challenge of the Word" by Dietrich; "Crisis and Hope" by Campi, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 149)
      - Emidio Campi / Ruth Harris Correspondence, 1977-1981 (Box 10, Folder 150)
      - WSCF Exco Meeting, Nairobi, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - Dossier, China Travel Diary, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 152)
      - WSCF Exco Meeting, Spode Hse, England, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 153)
    - Regional: Africa
      - WSCF Presence, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 154)
      - South Africa UCM Newsletter, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 155)
      - Joint Program of Africa Region and All Africa Conference of Churches, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 156)
    - Regional: Asia
      - "Developmental challenges in Asia and our Responsibilities", Asia Study Fellowship, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 157)
      - Asia Region Committee, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 158)
      - Special Report: "Wither the Indian SCM?", by C. Devanesen, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 159)
    - Regional: North America (NARC)
      - Main Documents, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 160)
      - Regional Papers, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 161)
      - Publication: "Women in the Struggle for Liberation", NARC Women's Project, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 162)
      - "Education for Change", NARC Project Report, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 163)
      - WSCF Committee, NARC, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 164)
      - Press On - Issues of NARC Newsletter, 1979-80 (Box 11, Folder 165)
  - The Eighties
    - Interregional
      - WSCF Funding Requests, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 166)
      - WSCF Host Committee for General Assembly, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 167)
      - General Assembly In San Francisco, CA, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 168)
      - General Assembly and Natioanal conference, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 169)
      - Minutes of General Assembly, San Francisco, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 170)
      - WSCF Annual Report, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 171)
      - Executive Committee, Mexico City, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 172)
      - General Assembly Minutes, Mexico City, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 173)
      - Officers Committee Minutes, Geneva, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 174)
      - WSCF Executive Committee Minutes, Toronto Canada, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 175)
      - WSCF North America Partners Consultation, Toronto, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 176)
      - WSCF Executive Comittee Minutes, Cairo, Egypt, Sept. 1-16, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 177)
      - WSCF Executive Committee Minutes, Cairo, Egypt, Sept. 13-23, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 178)
      - WSCF EXCO, Cairo, Egypt, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 179)
    - Regional: Asia / Pacific
      - Asia Regional Committee Meeting, Japan, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 180)
      - WSCF Asia Consultation with Christian Conference of Asia (CCA), 1982 (Box 12, Folder 181)
      - Asia / Pacific Human Resources Development Report, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 182)
      - WSCF Joint Consultation with CCA, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 183)
  - The Nineties
    - Interregional
      - WSCF General Assembly Report, Chantilly, France, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 184)
      - Program: Funding Requests, Ecumenical Assistance Program, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 185)
      - WSCF Executive Committee Minutes, Bangkok, Thailand, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 186)
      - "Life of the Movement" (Grey Book), 1992 (Box 12, Folder 187)
      - Consultation: "Reading the Signs of the Times", New York, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 188)
      - WSCF Executive Committee Meeting, Quito, Ecuador, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 189a)
      - Consultation on "University and the Christian Community"., 1993 (Box 13, Folder 189b)
      - WSCF Executive Committee, Poland (H. Ninast attended), 1994 (Box 13, Folder 190)
      - "Movement Building: Understand the WSCF" by S. Ariarajah, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 191)
      - WSCF General Assembly, Ivory Coast, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 192)
      - WSCF Senior Friends Meeting, Berlin, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 193-194)
      - WSCF Programme Book - Funding Request, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 195)
      - WSCF Executive Committee, St. Louis, MO, USA, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 196)
      - "Priorities of WSCF" Speech by Gigi Balan to United Methodist Women, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 197)
      - WSCF Federation News, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 198)
    - Regional: Asia / Pacific
      - Standing Committee Minutes, Malaysia (Box 13, Folder 199)
      - Regional Committee Minutes, Hongkong, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 200)
      - "East Asian Experience of the WSCF: 1931-61", By Frank Engel, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 201)
      - Regional Committee Minutes, New Delhi, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 202)
      - Joint Programme of Asia / Pacific WSCF and CCA; Report of Bangkok meeting, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 203)
      - Joint Program and Conference, Dossier 1 and 2 -"To Build and to Plant", 1995 (Box 13, Folder 204)
      - Regional Committee Minutes, Taiwan, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 205)
    - Regional: North America
      - Canadian SCM Publications, 1991-1993 (Box 13, Folder 206)
    - Women's Commission and Pre-Assemblies
      - Women's Pre-Assembly, San Francisco-Funding proposal to United Methodist Women for Women's Pre-Assembly, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 207)
      - Pre-Assembly Planning, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 208)
      - WSCF Women's Pre-Assembly, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 209)
      - WSCF Women's Commission and Interregional Program, 1983-1985 (Box 14, Folder 210)
      - Women Commission, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 211)
      - WSCF Women's Commission, Stony Point meeting NY, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 212)
      - Women's Commission Luncheon, NY, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 213)
      - Women's Pre-Assembly Report, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 214)
      - Women's Program, 1981-1986 (Box 14, Folder 215)
      - Women's Pre-Assembly Mexico City, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 216)
      - Interregional Women's program, 1986-1990 (Box 14, Folder 217)
      - Women's Commission Report At WSCF Exco-Committee, Toronto, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 218)
      - WSCF Women's Publications (Box 14, Folder 219)
      - WSCF Women's Pre-Assembly Cairo, Egypt, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 220)
      - WSCF Women's Pre-Assembly, Chantilly France, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 221)
    - WSCF Women's History Project
      - WSCF Women's History from 1994, by Terry Thompson (Box 14, Folder 222)
      - Planning of Women's History Project (1), 1993-1994 (Box 14, Folder 223-224)
      - Women's History Project Proposal (Box 15, Folder 225)
      - Literature Review of Women and Women's issues in WSCF, by Allison Brown, 1945-1982 (Box 15, Folder 226)
      - WSCF Co-Secretary General Model, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 227)
      - Women's History Project, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 228)
      - Women's History Project Funding Proposal, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 229)
      - Women's History meeting in NY, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 230)
      - History Project Articles On Women by Women (Box 15, Folder 231)
      - WSCF History Series #6, "Towards Womne's History", 1995 (Box 15, Folder 232)
    - Centennial Fund
      - Centennial Fund, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 233)
      - Centennial Fund By Laws, Statutes Guide and Guidelines for Investing (Box 15, Folder 234)
      - Centennial Fund- Basic Documents (Box 15, Folder 235)
      - Centennial Fund Trustees, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 236)
      - Centennial Fund Training, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 237)
      - Centennial Fund, 1994-1995 (Box 15, Folder 238-239)
      - Centennial Fund - Trustees Meeting and Investment Advisory Group, Geneva, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 240)
      - Centennial Fund, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 241)
      - Centennial Fund - Trustees Meeting, Geneva, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 242)
      - Centennial Fund - Trustees Meeting, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 243-244)
      - Centennial Fund - Trustees Meeting, Geneva, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 245)
    - WSCF Centennial History Project
      - History and Archives Project - Description and Budget, 1990-1995 (Box 16, Folder 246)
      - Printed Material (Box 16, Folder 247)
      - History Project, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 248)
      - Documents (R. Shuall), 1993 (Box 16, Folder 249)
      - History Working Group Minutes, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 250)
      - History Project, Betsy Anderson (Box 16, Folder 251)
      - Early Student Movement History In Asia, H.R. Weber, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 252)
      - WSCF Women's History Literature Review, 1945-1982 (Box 16, Folder 253)
    - Related Program: Frontier Internship in Mission Program (FIM)
      - Beginning and Constitution, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 254)
      - Evaluation after 10 years, 1961-1971 (Box 16, Folder 255)
      - North American Advisory Committee on FIM Program, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 256)
      - FIM Directory; FIM Seminary, Berlin, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 257)
      - Report to suppport Agencies, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 258)
      - FIM Books (Box 16, Folder 260)
- Addendum, Series IV
  - Program for "A Passion for Justice: An Evening Honoring Ruth Harris" with book launching of Journeys That Opened up the World: Women, Student Christian Movements and Social Justice, 1955-1975 (dedicated to Ruth Harris), 2003 (Box 18, Folder 281)
  - Obituary for Ruth Myrl Harris, 2013 (Box 18, Folder 281)